Developer Full-Stack PHP JS

🗣 Madrid, España 🗳 andersonbarbosadev@outlook.com 🛘 +34 624 85 01 73 🛅 in/anderson-barbosa-romero 🗢 andersonbarbosa.site

ANDERSON STIVEN BARBOSA ROMERO

Software engineer with over 7 years of experience in Full-Stack development, specializing in languages such as Python, PHP and JS, and database administration including MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle and MongoDB. My leadership has been evident in leading development teams, cultivating collaboration and ensuring the successful delivery of innovative projects.

My constant commitment to technology refreshment and passion for software engineering drives me to contribute significantly in challenging environments. Currently, I am ready to bring my experience and leadership to new projects that require a unique combination of technical and management skills.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

Quiktrak, LLC

January 2024 - Present, Madrid, España

- Development and maintenance of the company's platform, focusing on the implementation of microfrontends to improve the scalability and modularity of the system.
- · My focus to create efficient, scalable and high performance solutions that streamline the integration of new modules and improve the user experience.
- · Development of new modules and platform support.
- · Migration from a monolithic architecture to microfrontends without affecting the service.
- · Optimization of system performance and scalability.
- · Collaboration with a multidisciplinary team, including Product Managers, Backend Seniors, Tech Leads and Android Developers.

Software Engineer - Full Stack

Grupo TKS | Your digital auditors

May 2022 - December 2023, Madrid, España

- · Creation and execution of projects from scratch, demonstrating strong PHP and JavaScript skills.
- · Active participation in the support and continuous improvement of the company's core software, ensuring stability and optimal performance.
- · Close collaboration with multidisciplinary teams to ensure alignment of projects with the company's strategic objectives.

PHP Software Engineer

Bayport Colombia

August 2021 - April 2022, Bogotá, Colombia

- · Communication of intranet applications using the SOAP protocol, optimizing system integration and improving operational efficiency.
- · Key support in the company's core software, ensuring the stability and continued functionality of strategic applications.

EDUCATION

Máster in Big Data & Analytics

EAE Business School · Madrid, España · 2022

Engineering, Systems Engineering

Cooperative University of Colombia · Bogotá D.C · 2020

SKILLS

General: php, JavaScript, AngularJS, jQuery, Symfony Framework, Micro-frontends, MySQL, Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), Jenkins, Docker, Team Leadership, Strategic Planning, Project Management, SQL, Teamwork

Industry Knowledge: Symfony Framework, Nextjs, Project Management

Tools and technologies: php, JavaScript, AngularJS, jQuery, MySQL, Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), Jenkins, Docker, SQL

Interpersonal skills: Team leadership, Strategic planning, Team work